guitarguitar.co.uk 2019-06-04

# Our Privacy Promise and Policy

At guitarguitar, we believe in being open and transparent with our customers, so we have developed a Privacy Promise. This is a quick and simple summary of how we manage, share and store your information.

We promise to tell you how we use your data and that we will use it to keep your shopping experience as smooth and as simple as possible. Plus, we will make sure we collect and store your data securely.

#### Why we need a little information

To allow you to enjoy your purchase, we sometimes have to collect and keep a small amount of data, including your name, contact details, address, email address and payment details. We also have to share your data with organisations when necessary, including, but not limited to, our couriers, suppliers, repair technicians, payment providers, and finance providers. On occasion, we may additionally be required to share your details with local councils and authorities.

If we need your details, we promise to collect, process, store, and share your data safely and securely. We will also expect other businesses we work with to be just as careful with your data and not to use it for purposes you have not authorised. We will never hold onto your data for longer than is required and we will never sell your data to any 3rd party.

#### We will use data to make your purchase quick and easy

We will use the personal details that you share with us to let you know when online orders will be delivered, when in-store orders have arrived, for resolving issues regarding your order, for improving the processing of any servicing or warranties, for purchase preferences, for e-receipts, for audit and statistical analysis, and for other matters relating to the goods you have purchased. We may also ask for feedback on your purchase using our partners Feefo and Trustpilot if you have provided an email address.

#### If you have agreed separately, we may use your data to tell you about events and promotions

If you choose to receive marketing from guitarguitar, we can let you know when items are on sale, when there are special offers, or to tell you about new products and services we think might be of interest to you. 

#### You’re in control of your data

If you would like to stop receiving non-essential communications from us, you can amend your preferences at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link contained within email communications. 

You also have a right to see the data we hold on you. Please see our full Privacy Policy for details. If the information we hold on you is incorrect, you can email us at data.protection@guitarguitar.co.uk

Our full Privacy Policy, including all your rights, can be found at below. 

* * *

## Our Privacy Policy in full

guitarguitar is committed to protecting your safety and privacy, and takes its responsibilities regarding the security of customer information very seriously. This Privacy Policy explains what personal data we collect about you, how and why we use it, who we disclose it to, and how we protect your privacy.   

* * *

### 1\. Who is responsible for your data [back to top]   

This Privacy Policy only applies to the personal data that Guitar Guitar Limited has captured in-store or through our own website. It does not cover the privacy policies of partnering organisations who provide connected services (for example Barclays Partner Finance, DPD, Secure Trust Bank or Worldpay) and does not cover the privacy policies of linking sites found on our website. These companies may also gather information and you should consult their privacy policies where applicable.

References in this Privacy Policy to “guitarguitar”, “we”, “us” or “our” mean Guitar Guitar Limited (a company registered in Scotland with registration no SC247523, registered office at guitarguitar, 36 Trongate, Glasgow, G1 5ES). We control the ways your personal data is collected and the purposes for which your personal data is used by guitarguitar and are the “data controller” for the purposes of the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable European data protection legislation.   

* * *

### 2\. Personal data we collect about you [back to top]

When using the term “personal data”, “personal details”, or “your data” in our Privacy Policy, we mean information that relates to you and allows us to identify you, either directly or in combination with other information that we may hold. Your personal data may include for example your name, your contact details, information relating to your purchases (e.g. your order number or payment details) or information on how you use our website and how you interact with us. 

We collect some personal data from you, for example when you place an order online with us, use our website or when you contact us. We may also receive your personal data from our suppliers who provide products and services to you on our behalf (for example, for manufacture events or roadshows), our finance partners when you apply for finance or our other 3rd party services who act on our behalf (for example when you provide feedback on our products and services). If you purchase from us on behalf of someone else, you must have their consent to use their personal information.

For more information on the parties who may share your personal data with us, please see section 7. 

### Categories of data we collect

We may collect and process the following categories of information about you:

**Your name and your contact details**   
(email address, telephone number and postal address)

|   | 

When you create an account on our website or in-store

When you make a purchase 

When we process any services, repairs or warranties for you

When you take part in our competitions

When you make a general enquiry with us

When provided by a 3rd party you have authorised

When we are selling goods on your behalf

When you reserve goods from us  
  
---|---|---  

Information about your transaction, including your **payment details**

|   | 

When we are processing payments on your behalf, for example, refunds, deposits or purchases.

When provided by a 3rd party you have authorised.  
  
---|---|---  

**Advance Customer Information.** This information may include your nationality, your date of birth, your gender (where required) - identification documents (e.g. passport or ID), and proof of address

|   | 

We may ask you for these details in relation to, but not limited to, finance agreements, purchases or part exchanges. We typically do not retain such details  
  
---|---|---  

**The communications** you exchange with us (for example, your emails, letters, calls, or your messages on our online live chat service)

|   | 

When you contact us or you are contacted by us  
  
---|---|---  

Your posts and messages on **social media** directed to guitarguitar

|   | 

We may ask you for these details in relation to, but not limited to, finance agreements, purchases or part exchanges. We typically do not retain such details.  
  
---|---|---  

Your **feedback**

|   | 

When you reply to our requests for feedback or participate in our customer surveys  
  
---|---|---  

Your **wishlist items and interests**

|   | 

When you choose to provide this information to us  
  
---|---|---  

Information about **how you use our website** , such as, if you have any checkout problems or what products you are viewing on our website

|   | 

When you navigate on our website or click through from email communications  
  
---|---|---  

Your **Employment history, education, skills, experience, and, any other information related to job applications**

|   | 

When you choose to apply for a position with us.  
  
---|---|---  

**Sensitive personal data**

|   | 

We do not ask for, store or process any “Sensitive personal data” as defined under the UK Data Protection  
  
---|---|---  
  
### 3\. How and why we use your personal data [back to top]

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal data described in this Privacy Policy will depend on the personal data involved and the specific circumstances in which we collect it. However, we will usually collect personal data from you only   
\- when we have your consent to do so,   
\- when we need the personal data to perform a contract with you, or   
\- when there is a legal requirement to do so that is not overridden by your rights.

We will use the personal details that you share with us to let you know when online orders will be delivered, when in-store orders have arrived, for resolving issues, for improving the processing of any servicing or warranties, for purchase preferences, for e-receipts, for audit and statistical analysis, and for other matters relating to the goods you have purchased. We may also ask for feedback on your purchase if you have provided an email address. By submitting an order your personal details could be shared with various internal teams including sales, our stores, customer service and our warehouse fulfilment teams at guitarguitar. We also have to share your data with organisations when necessary, including, but not limited to, our couriers, suppliers, repair technicians, payment providers, and finance providers. On occasion, we may additionally be required to share your details with local councils and authorities.

If we require your details, we promise to collect, process, store, and share your data safely and securely. We will also expect other businesses we work with to be just as careful with your data and not to use it for purposes you have not authorised. We will never hold onto your data for longer than is required and we will never sell your data to any 3rd party. 

Moreover, we use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * **To manage your orders and provide our services to you**
    * When you purchase from us, we use your information to perform services in relation to providing your goods, for example to notify you of an order confirmation, to notify with issues with regards to your order, to issue you tracking numbers for your order, to validate your purchase and warranty, when we are selling goods on your behalf, and for legal, audit and accounting purposes. We will also use it to change your order details if you request such changes. 
    * In addition, we use your information when you use our related services, such as when we need to track an order in-transit with our couriers or for click and collect in our stores. 
    * We may also ask for advanced customer information when we need proof of address, when we are assisting you with a finance application or when conducting purchases or trade-ins. 

  * **To communicate with you and manage our relationship with you**
    * Occasionally we may need to contact you by email and/or telephone for administrative or operational reasons, for example in order to send you confirmation of your order and your payments, to inform you about any issues, to notify you when items are available and changes to your order. 
    * Please be aware that these communications are not made for marketing purposes and as such, you will continue to receive them even if you opt-out from receiving marketing communications. 
    * We will also use your personal data if we have to contact you after you have sent us a request, filled in a web-form through our website, emailed us, phoned us or contacted us on social media. 
    * Your opinion is very important to us, so we may send you an email to seek your feedback in relation to your purchased goods. 
    * We will use the communications you exchange with us and the feedback you provide in order to manage our relationship with you and to ensure a satisfactory customer experience. 

  * **To personalise and improve your customer experience**
    * We may use your personal data in order to tailor our services to your needs and preferences, and to provide you with a personalised customer experience. For example, if you inform us about your default delivery address, we will show that as your preferred location for delivery 
    * We may also collect information on how you use our website, which pages of our website you visit most, which products you search for and what products you buy, in order to understand your preferences. We may use this information to tailor the content and offers that you see on our website and, if you have agreed to receiving marketing communications, to send you relevant offers that we think you will like. 
    * If you are in the process of making a purchase, and it is not completed successfully, we may contact you to ensure you experienced no issues and provide assistance when required. 

  * **To inform you about news and offers that maybe of interest to you**
    * We may send you marketing communications for our events and promotions, if you have indicated that you are happy to receive these, for example when you create an account on our website or purchase from us and you express a wish to receive such communications. You can also request us to send you marketing communications through managing your preferences in your account. 
    * If you would like to stop receiving non-essential communications from us, you can amend your preferences at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link contained within email communications. 

  * **To inform 3rd parties of your name, contact details or purchase details when required**
    * We may send your name. contact details, and the details of the items you have ordered, to our suppliers in order for them to allow us to provide our services to you, these includes, but not limited to: 
      * couriers, product suppliers and other supply chain partners that facilitate the delivery of goods and our services to you
      * our payment services provider to process your order payment
      * our customer service software and management services if you contact us
    * We expect these businesses we work with to be just as careful with your data and not to use it for purposes you have not authorised. These suppliers should have their own privacy policies, which should be available on their websites, and which we suggest you familiarise yourself when required. 

  * **To improve our services, fulfil our administrative purposes and protect our business interests**
    * The business purposes for which we will use your information include accounting, billing and audit, credit or other payment card verification, fraud screening, safety, security and legal purposes, statistical and marketing analysis, systems testing, maintenance and development. 
    * We will also store your details when you choose to apply for employment with us.   

    * **To comply with our legal obligations** , for example, our obligation to provide your information to some local councils for part exchange audit purposes, provide proof of VAT exception/exports or to border control agencies. 

### 4\. Requesting access to your personal data [back to top]

Please contact guitarguitar’s Data Protection Officer to make a request under the Data Protection Act or EU data protection regulation or if you have any questions about your personal information. 

Data Protection Officer   
Guitar Guitar Limited   
36 Trongate,   
Glasgow   
G1 5ES   
United Kingdom   
Email: [data.protection@guitarguitar.co.uk](mailto:data.protection@guitarguitar.co.uk)

You have a right to request access to the personal data that we hold about you. If you would like to request a copy of your personal data, please visit our dedicated page for more information: <https://www.guitarguitar.co.uk/information/privacy-datarequest/>

We will response to your request within the legally required 40 days. A fee may be applicable. 

If, following our correspondence, you are unhappy with our response, you may contact the Information Commissioner. Details of how to take your complaint further can be found on the Information Commissioner’s website. <https://ico.org.uk/>

### 5\. Your Rights under the Data Protection Laws [back to top]

The EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) provides the following rights for individuals:

  1. The right to be informed by making it as clear as possible on how we will process data, who will process it, and where it could end up.
  2. The right to request access to the personal data we hold about you
  3. The right to correct inaccurate information held by us
  4. The right to deletion when data is no longer legitimately necessary
  5. The right to restrict processing, where relevant.
  6. The right to data portability, where you can request your data and ask for it to used elsewhere
  7. The right to object against any processing that is not required to undertake our contractual obligations.
  8. The right to restrict automated decision making and profiling.
  9. You can obtain further information about data protection and privacy laws by visiting the Information Commissioner’s website at: [https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/.](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/)

###  6\. Security of your personal data [back to top]

We are committed to taking appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal data against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage to personal data. When you provide your personal data through our website, this information is transmitted across the internet securely using current industry encryption standards.

Furthermore, guitarguitar is a PCI DSS compliant organisation. This means that we adhere to high security standards in order to protect your payment card details when you are sending us this information. 

As described in this Privacy Policy, we may in some instances disclose your personal data to third parties. Where guitarguitar discloses your personal data to a third party, we expect that third party to have appropriate technical and organisational measures in place to protect your personal data; however in some instances we may be compelled by law (or by the threat of legal action) to disclose your personal data to a third party, such as local councils and authorities, and have little influence control over how it is protected by that party.

The information that you provide to us will be held in our systems, which are located on our premises or those of an appointed third party. We may also allow access to your information by other third parties who act for us for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or for other purposes approved by you. Your personal data may be accessed by and processed outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) - including by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers (this includes staff engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, and the provision of support services). Where your personal data are transferred outside of the EEA, we require that appropriate safeguards are in place.

### 7\. Sharing your personal data [back to top]

We may share some of your personal data with, or obtain your personal data from, the following categories of third parties: 

  * **Product Suppliers and Distributors**   
We may for example send your information to suppliers and distributors to allow the fulfilment of you order, the customisation of your purchase, deal with any issues that have arisen from your purchase, to provide proof of purchase and, other matters relating to the services we provide. These details will only be used for the purposes you have authorised. 

  * **Payment Providers, Credit and Debit Card Companies**   
We share some of your personal data, which includes information about your method of payment and purchases, with your card provider. In order to ensure the security of your transactions and prevent or detect fraudulent transactions, we may also share your information with our fraud screening partners. 

  * **Suppliers providing services to us in order to help us run our business and improve our services and your customer experience.**   
We may for example share your personal data with the companies who provide repair services, run our email services, provide communication infrastructure or product customisation work. We may also disclose your information to the companies who help us get your feedback on our services. 

  * **Shopping Marketplaces and Auction websites**   
We may receive your data from 3rd party re-selling websites to allow the fulfilment of you order, the customisation of your purchase, deal with any issues that have arisen from your purchase, to provide proof of purchase and, other matters relating to the services we provide. These details will only be used for the purposes you have authorised. 

  * **Finance Providers**   
We share some of your personal data, which includes information about your contact details and the goods you wish to purchase, with our finance providers so they can process agreements accordingl 

  * **Couriers**   
We share some of your personal data, which includes information about your contact details and delivery address, with our couriers so they can delivery your purchases, process any damage claims and process collections on our behalf. 

  * **Email Provider, Customer Relationship Management and Livechat software**   
To allow you to efficiently communicate with us, sometimes your data will be shared through a 3rd party provider. For example, any emails sent with your personal details will be processed through our email provider. 

  * **In-Store Roland Planets (Glasgow Only)**   
In-store, a Roland Planet employee may process your personal details on our behalf. They work in partnership with us to improve your experience in selected stores. They will not share your data outside of guitarguitar unless you have explicitly opted-in separately. 

### 8\. Retention of your Personal Details [back to top]

We will retain your personal data for as long as we need it in order to fulfil our purposes set out in this Privacy Policy or in order to comply with the law under EU and national consumer rights regulation or until relevant storage requirements from financial and tax authorities expire. When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it.   

### 9\. Transmission of information to us outwith our control [back to top]

Please be aware that we cannot always guarantee the security of the information sent to us via the internet before transmitted to our website or services, any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your details,we will use industry standards to prevent unauthorised access. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not always completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee the security of your information before it is transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.   

### 10\. Links to other Websites [back to top]

To help provide the information you need to support your purchases and the services we offer, our website may contain links to other websites of interest. Please note that we do not have any control over those websites, as such, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any personal data which you provide whilst visiting such sites. Please exercise caution and review their applicable privacy policies accordingly.

### 11\. Cookies or other tracking technologies [back to top]

We use cookies in our website and in our emails. Cookies are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. They enable you to navigate on our website and allow you to purchase online. You can delete cookies if you wish; while certain cookies are necessary for viewing and purchasing, most of the features will be still accessible without cookies.

In order to improve our services and to provide you with more relevant content and to analyse how visitors use our website, we may use technologies, such as cookies, pixels or tracking software. Please be aware that in most cases we will not be able to identify you from the information we collect using these technologies. 

For example, we use software to monitor customer traffic patterns and website usage to help us develop the design and layout of the website in order to enhance the experience of the visitors to our website. This software does not enable us to collect any personal data. In addition, in order to understand how our customers interact with the emails and the content that we send, we use pixels that allow us to know if the emails we send are opened or if the content of our emails is displayed in text or html form. 

For more information on how we use cookies and how you can remove them, read our Cookie Policy

### 12\. Updates to our Privacy Policy [back to top]

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time, including as part of the new European data protection legislation which will apply from 25 May 2018 (the “General Data Protection Regulation”) - we will update the Privacy Policy and we will publish on our website any new version of this Policy so please review it frequently.

### 13\. Your Consent [back to top]

By continuing to use guitarguitar, you are agreeing to the terms detailed within our Privacy Policy and you are consenting to the collection, storage, processing and sharing of your personal data and other information on the basis set out above.
